Optimization is all about eliminating instructions that are not needed,
优化的目的 是消除不需要的指令
while still getting the result you expect from your program.
同时保证程序可以输出你想要的结果
The fewer times that a program has to access memory and perform calculations,
程序访问内存和执行计算的次数越少
the more efficient your program will be.
程序效率越高
Optimization isn't just about shoving your code through
优化不是简单地将你的代码乱塞在某个黑盒子里
some black box until its performance increases,
等待它的效率提升
it's about knowing how a computer works and executes your code,
你还需要了解计算机工作原理 并执行代码
and using that knowledge to your advantage.
并重复利用这些知识
Besides a storage medium like your hard drive,
除了硬盘之类的存储介质之外
a computer basically has two parts that are relevant to running your programs.
电脑基本上有两个硬件与运行程序相关
The CPU and RAM.
CPU 和 RAM
The CPU or central processing unit,
CPU 或中央处理单元
has a section called the control unit,
有一个部分叫做控制单元
which carries out the instructions contained in your code.
它执行你代码中包含的指令
Another section known as the arithmetic logic unit,
另一部分称为算术逻辑单元
calculates mathematical and logical expressions.
它负责计算数学和逻辑表达式
RAM or random access memory,
RAM 或随机存取存储器
is what your program uses to store your variables and
用于程序存储变量和指令
instructions to support the execution of your program.
从而支持程序的执行
It is a storage medium like your hard drive,
这是一个存储介质 就像你的硬盘
but it has much faster read and write times and is volatile.
但是它的读写速度要快得多 而且是易失的
Which means that when you turn your computer off,
这意味着当你关闭计算机时
all the data disappears.
一切数据都会消失
Imagine if your hard drive did that every time you turned your computer off.
想象一下 你的硬盘驱动器在你每次关机的时候也是这样吗？
In essence, the control unit in the CPU will read
简而言之 CPU 中的控制单元将读取
the next instruction in your code and execute it by writing data to ram,
代码中的下一条指令 并通过将数据写入 RAM
reading data from RAM,
来执行该指令
or have the arithmetic or logic unit perform a calculation.
或者让算术或逻辑单元进行计算
Unlike Python, when you finish writing a program in C++,
与 Python 不同 当你用 C++ 编写程序时
it needs to be compiled before you can execute it.
在你执行指令之前 需要进行编译
The compiler rewrites your code into a set of
编译器将你的代码重写成一组
instructions that the CPU can understand called machine code,
CPU 可以理解的指令 称为机器码
which is basically the language of the CPU.
这就是 CPU 的语言
So a compiler is basically acting as
所以 编译器实际上发挥了翻译作用
a translator between how you understand and write code,
将你如何理解和编写代码
and how the CPU understands and reads code.
与 CPU 如何理解和读取代码连接起来
For example, you might write the line int x equals five,
例如 你可能会写 int x = 5 这行代码
the compiler would turn this line of code into something like this.
而编译器会把这行代码变成这样
And the CPU would understand that to mean store the value of
而CPU就会明白 这表示
five to a specific location in RAM that
将 5 的值存储于 RAM 的特定位置
can be accessed with an address tied to the variable x.
该位置可以通过绑定到变量 X 的地址访问
Another instruction would be able to retrieve the value of X by sending
另一条指令发送一条指令到 CPU
an instruction to the CPU that would query the value stored at the address tied to X.
然后 CPU 将询问存储在与 X 相关的地址处的值 即可检索 X 的值
And another instruction could take the value stored at the address for X,
而另一条指令可以将地址中存储的值视作 X
incremented by 10, and then update the new value in memory.
增加 10 然后更新内存中的新值
All of these instructions take time to execute.
所有这些指令都需要时间来执行
And some operations like Trigonometric functions and branches
还有一些像三角函数和 IF 语句分支的操作
of an IF statement are known to be particularly inefficient.
这些都是特别低效的
Let's take a series of IF statements.
我们来看一系列的 IF 语句
Here we have an assignment of the variable y based on the value of x.
这里 我们根据 x 的值来赋值变量 y
This code is inefficient because it causes the CPU to compare the value of x twice.
这段代码效率很低 因为它会导致 CPU 两次对比 x 的值
However, if the first condition is false,
但是 如果第一个条件为 false
the second condition is automatically true.
第二个条件就会自动成立的
Therefore an optimization would be to rewrite
因此 优化时 我们需要重写
the IF statements with an IF else statement like the following.
IF语句 具体如下所示
This version of the code only needs to do one comparison.
这个版本的代码则只需要做一次比较
You might be thinking that such a small change won't make much of a difference in speed,
你可能会认为 这么小的变化在速度上并没有太大的差别
and with a single occurrence like this, it probably won't.
如果只运行一次 可能差别真的不大
But imagine if these statements were inside a four loop
但想象一下 如果这些语句是在 for 循环内
that ran thousands or millions of times.
运行数千或数百万次
Small inefficiencies definitely start to add up.
那么这种低效的代码肯定会造成整个程序的效率低下
Understanding how the computer operates helps you
了解计算机如何运作可以帮助你
determine which calculations might be slowing your program down.
确定哪些计算可能会拖慢你的程序
The more insight you have into what was happening inside the computer,
对计算机内部发生的事情了解更深刻
the more successful you'll be at increasing the efficiency of your programs.
你就能更成功地提高程序的效率